<quiz>
<question>
<q> What year was the 19th Amendment to the Constitution ratified, guaranteeing American women citizens the right to vote? It was quietly signed into law in a ceremony to which the press and suffragists were not invited. </q>
		<answer>1910</answer>
		<answer>1935</answer>
		<answer>1920</answer>
		<correct>3</correct>
	</question>

	<question>
		<q>She took her job as "First Lady" seriously, traveling the country and the world to gather information about the problems and concerns of workers, children, minorities, and the poor. She wrote a daily newspaper column and made frequent radio broadcasts. Who was this active wife of a president?</q>
		<answer>Eleanor Roosevelt</answer>
		<answer> Jackie Kennedy </answer>
		<answer> Abigail Adams </answer>
		<correct>1</correct>
	</question>



<question>
		<q>In 1965, the Supreme Court overturned one of the last state laws prohibiting the prescription or use of contraceptives by married couples, which was... </q>
<answer>Webster v. Reproductive Health Services</answer>
<answer>Griswold v. Connecticut</answer>
<answer>Planned Parenthood v. Casey</answer>
<correct>2</correct>
	</question>




	<question>
		<q> "The history of mankind is a history of repeated injuries and usurpations on the part of man toward woman, having in direct object the establishment of an absolute tyranny over her. To prove this, let facts be submitted to a candid world."  This passage is from: </q>
		<answer> The Equal Rights Amendment</answer>
		<answer> The first Women's Rights Convention </answer>
		<answer> The Declaration of Sentiments </answer>
		<correct>3</correct>
	</question>

<question>
		<q> She came to the U.S. when she was a teenager to study science and stayed to become "the world's foremost female experimental physicist." Her most famous experiment disproved what had been thought to be a fundamental scientific law. Who is this outstanding Asian-American scientist? </q>
		<answer> Yu-Cheng Lu</answer>
		<answer> Yu-Chi Chen </answer>
		<answer> Chien-Shiung Wu </answer>
		<correct>3</correct>
	</question>


<question>
		<q> In what year did astronomer Maria Mitchell become the first woman elected to the American Academy of Arts and Sciences?</q>
		<answer>1949</answer>
		<answer>1849</answer>
		<answer>1906</answer>
		<correct>2</correct>
	</question>


<question>
		<q>Margaret Sanger organized the American Birth Control League in what year?</q>
		<answer>1920</answer>
		<answer>1921</answer>
		<answer>1935</answer>
		<correct>2</correct>
	</question>

<question>
		<q>With this case, the Supreme Court affirms the right of states to deny public funding for abortions and to prohibit public hospitals from performing abortions. </q>
<answer>Webster v. Reproductive Health Services</answer>
<answer>Griswold v. Connecticut</answer>
<answer>Planned Parenthood v. Casey</answer>
<correct>1</correct>
	</question>


<question>
		<q>In what year did the U.S. Congress declare March to be National Women's History Month?</q>
		<answer>1969</answer>
		<answer>1982</answer>
		<answer>1987</answer>
		<correct>3</correct>
	</question>


<question>
		<q>She opened "Hull House" in a run-down Chicago neighborhood, a community center to improve conditions for poor immigrants. The program of English-language classes, childcare, health education and recreational opportunities soon inspired hundreds of other settlement houses throughout
the country. Her name?</q>
		<answer>Abigail Adams</answer>
		<answer> Jane Addams </answer>
		<answer> Mary Harris </answer>
		<correct>2</correct>
	</question>


<question>
		<q> Unwilling to commit to a vigorous travel schedule until her children were grown, ? wrote many of her speeches for delivery by ?. </q>
		<answer> Elizabeth Cady Stanton, Susan B. Anthony </answer>
<answer> Elizabeth Cady Stanton, Lucricia Mott </answer>
		<answer> Susan B. Anthony, Elizabeth Cady Stanton </answer>
		<correct>1</correct>
	</question>


<question>
		<q>Who is the founder of Women on Waves?</q>

<answer>Rebecca Feraldo</answer>
<answer>Rebecca Carson</answer>
<answer>Rebecca Gomperts</answer>

<correct>3</correct>
	</question>



<question>
		<q>"He has endeavored, in every way that he could to destroy her confidence in her own powers, to lessen her self-respect, and to make her willing to lead a dependent and abject life."  This was written by: </q>
<answer>Susan B. Anthony</answer>
<answer>Elizabeth Cady Stanton</answer>
<answer>Abigal Adams </answer>

<correct>2</correct>
	</question>


<question>
		<q>"A Convention to discuss the social, civil and religious condition and rights of woman, was held in the Wesleyan Chapel, at ?, N.Y.</q>

<answer>Syracuse</answer>
<answer>Seneca Falls</answer> 
<answer>Auburn</answer>
<correct>2</correct>
	</question>







<question>
		<q> What year did California adopt the nation's first "no fault" divorce law, allowing couples to divorce by mutual consent? </q>
		<answer>1959</answer>
		<answer>1969</answer>
		<answer>1979</answer>
		<correct>2</correct>
	</question>


<question>
		<q>One of the most important Union spies and scouts during the Civil War was a Black woman who had escaped from slavery. Can you name her?</q>
		<answer> Harriet Tubman </answer>
		<answer> Maya Angelou </answer>
		<answer> Lucinda Douglas </answer>
		<correct>1</correct>
	</question>


<question>
		<q> What year did Dr. Benjamin Spock eliminate sex-bias in his revised Baby and Child Care. </q>
		<answer>1966</answer>
		<answer>1973</answer>
		<answer>1976</answer>
		<correct>3</correct>
	</question>


<question>
		<q> Where was the first national women's liberation conference held?
</q>
		<answer> Chicago </answer>
		<answer> New York </answer>
		<answer> Washington, DC </answer>
		<correct>1</correct>
	</question>


<question>
		<q> Which state became the first to re-legalize abortion?
 </q>
		<answer> Texas </answer>
		<answer> California </answer>
		<answer> New York </answer>
		<correct>2</correct>
	</question>


<question>
		<q> Who was the first Black woman elected to the U.S. Congress?
 </q>
		<answer> Sarah Palmolove </answer>
		<answer> Barbara Lee </answer>
		<answer> Shirley Chisholm </answer>
		<correct>3</correct>
	</question>


<question>
		<q> Who was the first Asian-American woman elected to the U.S. Congress? </q>
		<answer> Patsy Mink</answer>
		<answer> Betty Wu </answer>
		<answer> Maya Lin </answer>
		<correct>1</correct>
	</question>


<question>
		<q> Who wrote The Feminine Mystique?</q>
		<answer> Gloria Steinem </answer>
		<answer> Betty Friedan </answer>
		<answer> Jane Addams </answer>
		<correct>2</correct>
	</question>


<question>
		<q> For the first time in history, more women than men enter college in what year?</q>
		<answer>1982</answer>
		<answer>1970</answer>
		<answer>1978</answer>
		<correct>3</correct>
	</question>


<question>
		<q> What year did the groundbreaking law, marital rape, become a crime in Nebraska?</q>
		<answer>1980</answer>
		<answer>1969</answer>
		<answer>1976</answer>
		<correct>3</correct>
	</question>



<question>
		<q>Daughter and granddaughter of Paiute Indian chiefs from Nevada, she lobbied Congress, wrote extensively, and traveled across country during the late 1800s lecturing on the hardships brought upon Native Americans by the U.S. Government. Her name?</q>
		<answer>Pokatu Fallon</answer>
		<answer>Sarah Winnemucca </answer>
		<answer>Bethany Gerlach</answer>
		<correct>2</correct>
	</question>



<question>
		<q>Which mother led a 125-mile march of child workers all the way from the mills of Pennsylvania to President Theodore Roosevelt's vacation home on Long Island?</q>
		<answer> Susan B. Anthony </answer>
		<answer> Mary Harris </answer>
		<answer> Abigal Adams</answer>
		<correct>2</correct>
	</question>



<question>
	<q> What are some of the side effects of Norplant?</q>
		<answer> Rapidly growing toenails</answer>
		<answer> Thinning hair </answer>
		<answer> Cardiovascular and breast cancer risks </answer>
		
		<correct>3</correct>
	</question> 

<question> 
<q> She is regarded as the greatest ballerina born in America. Her father was the Chief of the Osage Indians. Can you name her?</q>

<answer>Maria Tallchief </answer>

<answer>Sarah Winnemucca</answer>

<answer>Rachael Carson</answer>

<correct>1</correct>
</question>


<question>
	<q> Who gave a spontaneous "Ain't I a Woman?" speech at the woman's rights convention in Akron, Ohio? </q>
		<answer> Mary Harris </answer>
		<answer> Sojouner Truth </answer>
		<answer> Susan B. Anthony </answer>
		
		<correct>2</correct>
	</question> 

<question>
	<q> Who printed the first copy of the Declaration of Independence that
included the signers' names?</q>
		<answer> Mary Katherine Goddard </answer>
		<answer> Abigail Adams </answer>
		<answer> Mary Harris </answer>
		
		<correct>1</correct>
	</question>

<question>
	<q>Before the 1960s, farm workers in the U.S. were not paid the minimum wage and had no influential representatives to fight for their rights. Who played a part in changing this situation?</q>
		<answer> Mary Harris </answer>
		<answer> Dolores Huerta </answer>
		<answer> Dorthea Lange </answer>

		<correct>2</correct>
	</question>



<question> 
<q> Emergency Contraception...</q>
<answer>causes an abortion </answer>
<answer>causes a miscarriage</answer>
<answer>prevents egg fertilization within 120 hours of sex</answer>

<correct>3</correct>
</question>

</quiz>
